Contact

ashish@ashishgupta.co.uk

www.linkedin.com/in/ ashishguptame (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Artificial Intelligence (AI)
Management Consulting
Trading

Certifications

How to Use Generative AI: Building an AI-First Mindset

Ashish Gupta

Board Advisor | Al & Tech Strategy | Investor | Former Managing Director at UBS

London, England, United Kingdom

Summary

Senior executive with over 20 years of experience in financial services and technology transformation. Currently providing board-level advisory services with expertise that spans derivatives trading, platform strategy, and business transformation across multiple asset classes. Track record of scaling global platforms, having led global trading businesses and digital transformation initiatives at UBS. Recognized for combining traditional banking expertise with innovative technologies including AI, DeFi, and Confidential Computing. Active startup investor and board advisor with a focus on transforming financial services through technology innovation.

Experience

Aspiro Consulting Ltd
Founder | Strategy Consultant
August 2024 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Board-level advisor specializing in AI strategy, business transformation, and technology-driven growth across enterprises, fintechs, and government bodies.

Business transformation & Growth – Fundraising, acquisitions, product innovation

Al & platform strategy – Scalable Al adoption, governance, and monetization # Enterprise technology – Building future-proof, scalable platforms across industries

UBS

21 years 2 months

Managing Director - Global Head of Digital Platforms for Derivatives January 2020 - August 2024 (4 years 8 months)

Responsible for the global Structured Products and Solutions platforms, overseeing strategy, investment decisions and delivery.

Managed the cross asset product team and a 500-person technology division. Successfully leading the reorganisation of these teams, including the integration of Credit Suisse.

Strategically transformed these platforms through development of an API-first strategy, a common backbone across businesses and the early adoption of emerging technologies. As a result client AUM on electronic channels grew by 250% and the time to market of new products reduced by 60%.

Member of Derivatives Management Committee & Digital Platforms Management Committee

Global Head of Actively Managed Certificates Trading March 2018 - July 2020 (2 years 5 months) London, United Kingdom

Led the UBS AMC trading business, growing AUM by 300% over 4 years and transforming the platform into a globally recognised solution.

Global Head of Commodities Trading January 2016 - July 2020 (4 years 7 months) London

Global commodities franchise trading index products, structured products and vanilla options.

Managed trading books and strategy for private clients, institutions and corporations. And grew the Commodity ETC and ETF AUM into one of the largest commodity offerings globally.

Member of various Index Governance committees (BCOM, CMCI, RIGI), Equities Trading Committee, Equities Diversity and Inclusion, Derivatives Operating Forum and Lead for Cultural Action Stream.

Executive Director - Head of Structured Commodities Trading May 2011 - January 2016 (4 years 9 months)

Director - Rates & FX Structured Trading June 2004 - May 2011 (7 years)

Industrial Placement July 2003 - June 2004 (1 year)

6 month Placement working on the Securitisation desk in Debt Capital Markets

Education

University of Oxford, Keble College
MEng, Engineering, Economics and Management · (2000 - 2004)

Eton College

(1995 - 2000)

BPP Law School

Diploma in Law · (2007 - 2009)

Saïd Business School, University of Oxford Oxford Blockchain Strategy Programme · (2019)

BCS, The Chartered Institute for IT

Data Analyst Level 4, Data Science · (2019 - 2021)